Friedlander, Walter A.; Papers ger003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence files, 1918-1984; 2; 3,383 folders
  - Professional correspondence, 1933-1984; 2.2; 1391 folders containing approx. 21,788 items of correspondence
    - Professional correspondence (selection based on volume or importance of individual correspondent), 1933-1984; 2.2.1
      - Leo, Wilhelm G., 1933-1945 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 186)
        Leo, Friede, 1946-1961.
        See also International Rescue and Relief Committee; Margraff, Else; Selfhelp of Emigres from Central Europe, Inc.
      - * Levy, Paul
        See Lynn, Paul.
      - Lohmann, Rosemargrit, 1973-1979 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 187)
      - Lohmann, Rosemargrit, 1980-1984 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 188)
      - Lynn, Paul, 1931-1957 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 189)
        Lynn, William, 1958.
      - Maas, Henry, 1953-1984 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 190)
        Maas, Judy.
      - Magnus, Erna, 1933-1969 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 191)
      - Maier, Henry W., 1962-1963 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 192)
        Maier, Jeanne.
      - Maier, Henry W., 1964-1977 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 193)
      - Maier, Margaret E., 1965-1971 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 194)
      - Maier, Max Hermann, 1962-1965 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 195)
      - Maraun, Erna, 1947-1953 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 196)
      - Maraun, Erna, 1954-1959 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 197)
      - Marck, Siegfried, 1940-1955 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 198)
        Marck, Ilse, 1940-1971.
      - Marcus, Ernest, 1954-1981 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 199)
      - Margraff, Else, 1941-1946 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 200)
        Margraff, Christian Alfons.
      - Marschak, Jakob, 1942-1977 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 201)
        Marschak, Marianne, 1942-1982.
      - Matsdorf, Hilde née Meyerowitz, 1939-1981 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 202)
        Matsdorf, Wolf S.
      - Matull, Wilhelm, 1964-1979 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 203)
      - Mayer-Kulenkampff, Lina, 1948-1962 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 204)
      - Mende, Käthe, 1937-1954 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 205)
      - Mende, Käthe, 1955-1963 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 206)
      - Mende, Käthe (Memorial service), 1963-1964 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 207)
      - * Meyerowitz, Hilde
        See Matsdorf, Hilde
      - Meyerowitz, Thea, 1935 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 208)
      - Middendorff, Wolf, 1958-1983 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 209)
        Middendorff, Dorothee.
      - Mierendorff, Marta, 1975-1979 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 210)
      - Mierendorff, Marta, 1980-1984 (Box 11 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 211)
      - Miller, Susanne, 1973-1977 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 212)
      - Miller, Susanne, 1978-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 213)
      - Miran, Bernard, 1945-1967 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 214)
        Miran, Anne.
      - Miran, Bernard, 1970-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 215)
      - Müller, C. Wolfgang, 1968-1983 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 216)
        Müller-Bilitza, Brigitte.
      - Münke, Stephanie, 1957-1971 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 217)
      - Muthesius, Hans, 1933; 1951-1977 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 218)
      - Nachbauer, Kurt, 1950-1982 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 219)
      - Naparstok-Ruecker, Esther, 1957-1979 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 220)
      - Naparstok-Ruecker, Esther, 1980-1982 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 221)
      - Naparstok-Ruecker, Esther, 1983-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 222)
      - Nathan, Otto, 1935-1937; 1975-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 223)
      - Nemitz, Kurt, 1960-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 224)
      - Newman, Wilson, 1937-1954 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 225)
        Newman, Helen.
      - Newman, Wilson, 1955-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 226)
      - Niedrig, Heinz (Arbeiterwohlfahrt), 1975-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 227)
      - Nörenberg, Ruth, 1957-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 228)
      - Nowotny, Fausta, 1966-1977 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 229)
        Nowotny, Karl A.
      - Nowotny, Fausta, 1978-1981 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 230)
      - Nowotny, Fausta, 1982-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 231)
      - Ollendorff, Henry, 1946-1979 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 232)
      - Ontell, Robert (Bob), 1950-1977 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 233)
        Ontell, Sione M.
      - Ontell, Robert, 1978-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 234)
      - Oppenheimer, Luise, 1942-1978 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 235)
        Oppenheimer, Walter.
      - Oswalt, August, 1935-1970 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 236)
        Oswalt, Elisabeth.
      - Oswalt, August, 1971-1983 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 237)
        Oswalt, Elisabeth, 1971-1984.
      - Otto, Adolf, 1936-1937 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 238)
      - Pakuscher, Ernst K., 1957-1980 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 239)
        Pakuscher, Eva Nolde.
      - Parker, Martha Eva (Prochownik), 1936-1959 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 240)
      - Pennekamp, Marianne, 1965-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 241)
      - Pense, Rudolf (Deutscher Verein für öffentliche und private Fürsorge), 1952-1962 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 242)
      - Pense, Rudolf, 1963-1967 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 243)
      - Pense, Rudolf, 1970-1979 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 244)
        See also International Council on Social Welfare; Lecture Project, 1955-1956; Munich Conference, 1956; Helene Simon.
      - Pfaffenberger, Hans, 1959-1969 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 245)
      - Pfeifenberger, Werner, 1974-1980 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 246)
      - Pfeifenberger, Werner, 1981-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 247)
      - Pietzner, Walter, 1968-1979 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 248)
      - Pietzner, Walter, 1980-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 249)
      - Plank, Robert, 1948-1959 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 250)
        Plank, Nuschi.
      - Plank, Robert, 1960-1983 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 251)
      - Platiel, Nora, 1953-1979 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 252)
      - Poelchau, Harald, 1952-1966 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 253)
        Poelchau, Dorothee.
      - Poelchau, Harald, 1967-1972 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 254)
        Poelchau, Dorothee, 1967-1977.
      - Poelchau, Harald S., Jr., 1967-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 255)
        Poelchau, Susan.
      - Pollack, Betty Gillespie, 1968-1984 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 256)
        Pollack, Dave.
      - Pongratz, Ludwig J., 1976-1982 (Box 12 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 257)
      - Quast, Sofie (Archiv für Wohlfahrtspflege Soziale Arbeit), 1952-1982 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 258)
      - Rawiel, Käthe, 1950-1971 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 259)
      - Rawiel, Käthe, 1972-1979 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 260)
      - Rawiel, Käthe, 1980-1984 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 261)
      - * Razovsky, Cecilia
        See Davidson, Cecilia Razovsky
      - Read, Ruth, 1944-1970 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 262)
        Read, Stanley.
      - Read, Ruth, 1972-1984 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 263)
      - Reichert, Kurt, 1944-1984 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 264)
        Reichert, Betty.
      - Reinemann, John Otto, 1928 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 265)
        Reinemann, Hertha.
      - Reinemann, John Otto, 1933-1936 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 266)
      - Reinemann, John Otto, 1937-1941 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 267)
      - Reinemann, John Otto, 1942-1948 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 268)
      - Reinemann, John Otto, 1949-1953 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 269)
      - Reinemann, John Otto, 1954-1958 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 270)
      - Reinemann, John Otto, 1959-1963 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 271)
      - Reinemann, John Otto, 1964-1970 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 272)
      - Reinemann, John Otto, 1971-1975 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 273)
      - Reinemann, Hertha, 1976-1980 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 274)
      - Reinemann, Hertha, 1981-1984 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 275)
      - Reisner, Else, 1957-1984 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 276)
      - Reisner, Konrad (Conrad), 1933; 1938-1964; 1981 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 277)
        Reisner, Gertrud.
      - Rexin, Manfred, 1979-1981 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 278)
      - Rexin, Manfred, 1982-1984 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 279)
      - Rice, Richardson (Dick) L., 1942; 1959; 1973-1983 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 280)
      - * Richter, Hilde
        See Köster, Hilde
      - Richter, Margaret (Maggie), 1946-1984 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 281)
        Richter, Karl.
      - Rickenbach, Walter (Schweizerische Gemeinnützige Gesellschaft), 1936-1981 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 282)
      - Riesenfeld, Arthur J. (Gocki), 1977 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 283)
        Riesenfeld, Stella.
      - Riesenfeld, Sonia, 1935-1967 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 284)
      - Rinner, Erich (Deutschland-Berichte), 1936-1941 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 285)
      - Rive-Johansen, Marion (Marid), 1934-1979 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 286)
      - Rive-Johansen, Marion (Marid), 1980-1984 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 287)
      - Ronald, Margot, 1935-1966 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 288)
      - Ronald, Margot, 1967-1983 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 289)
      - Rosenfeld, Kurt, 1934-1945 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 290)
        Rosenfeld, Alice.
      - Rosenheim, Kate, 1944-1961 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 291)
      - Rosenheim, Kate, 1962-1982 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 292)
        Rosenheim, Hilde.
      - Salomon, Alice, 1947 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 293)
      - * Salzberger-Wittenberg, Isca
        See Wittenberg, Isca
      - Schiller, Heinrich, 1962-1983 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 294)
      - Schmoeckel, Johanna (Hanna), 1946-1968 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 295)
      - Schottland, Charles, 1954-1980 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 296)
        Schottland, Edna.
      - Schroeder, Luise, 1954-1957 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 297)
        Photo, 1919.
      - Schulze, Emma, 1949-1976 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 298)
      - Schulze, Oskar, 1939-1971 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 299)
        Schulze, Susanne (Suse).
      - Schwendtke, Arnold, 1977-1980 (Box 13 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 300)
      - * Seger, Gerhart A.
        See Neue Volks-Zeitung
      - Seipp, Paul, 1961-1980 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 301)
        Seipp, Beate.
      - Siegmund-Schultze, Friedrich, 1952-1969 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 302)
        Siegmund-Schultze, Maria, 1970.
      - Sievers, Max (Freies Deutschland), 1937-1940 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 303)
      - Sieverts, Rudolf, 1954-1963 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 304)
      - Sieverts, Rudolf, 1964-1979 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 305)
        Sieverts, Elisabeth, 1980-1981.
      - Simon, Helene, 1937-1946; (originals and copies) (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 306)
        Marx, Moses, 1959.
        Transcripts of letters from Helene Simon to her sister, Mrs. Gertrude Marx, 1888-1893.
      - Simonsohn, Berthold, 1966-1977 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 307)
        Simonsohn, Trude, 1978-1980.
      - Solltmann, Idamarie, 1919-1928; 1940; 1977-1978 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 308)
        Wittfogel, Karl August.
      - Splittgerber, Erna, 1952-1979 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 309)
      - Stammer, Otto, 1957-1977 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 310)
        Stammer, Martha, 1957-1978.
        See also Lecture Project, 1955-1956.
      - Stanne, Peter, 1952-1983 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 311)
        Stanne, Dilys.
      - Steiger, Emma (Emmy), 1933-1936 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 312)
      - Steiger, Emma, 1937-1951 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 313)
      - Steiger, Emma, 1952-1972 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 314)
      - Steiner, John Michael, 1962-1975 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 315)
        Steiner, Ulrike.
      - Steiner, John Michael, 1976-1984 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 316)
      - Stephan, Adolf, 1947-1980 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 317)
      - Svarc, Ivor, 1957-1969 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 318)
        Svarc, Flora.
      - Svarc, Ivor, 1971-1984 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 319)
      - Tarail, Theodore (Ted), 1969-1977 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 320)
      - Taylor, Hasseltine, 1946-1984 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 321)
        Taylor, Archer.
      - Tennstedt, Florian, 1977 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 322)
      - Tennstedt, Florian, 1978-1979 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 323)
        See also Leibfried, Stephen.
      - Tennstedt, Florian, 1980-1984 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 324)
      - * Thomas, Fanny (Fanja)
        See Jeserka, Fanja.
      - Tillich, Paul, 1938-1941 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 325)
        Tillich, Hannah, 1950.
        Fraenkel, Hilde, 1941.
      - Trotha, Margarete von, 1972-1983 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 326)
        Trotha, Christoph von.
      - Tugend (Tugendreich), Irene, 1939-1976 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 327)
        Tugend, Gustav.
      - Tugend, Thomas (Tom), 1952-1983 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 328)
      - Vetterli (Hensel), Alice (Lix), 1937-1978 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 329)
      - Vetterli, Alice, 1979-1983 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 330)
      - Wachenheim, Hedwig, 1931-1939 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 331)
      - Wachenheim, Hedwig, 1940-1959 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 332)
      - Wachenheim, Hedwig, 1960-1969 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 333)
      - Waldman, Dan, 1959-1982 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 334)
        Waldman, Gina.
      - Waldman, Hans (Howard L), 1961-1984 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 335)
        Waldman, Else.
      - Waldman, Michael, 1969 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 336)
        Waldman, Ute.
      - Walz, Reinhold, 1973-1984 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 337)
      - * Weiland, Ruth
        See Freeman, Ruth.
      - Weiss (White), Jeannette, 1960-1983 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 338)
        Weiss (White), Ernst (Ernest).
      - Weisser, Gerhard (Forschungsinstitut für Gesellschaftspolitik und beratende Sozialwissenschaft e.V), 1955-1974 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 339)
      - Weisser, Gerhard, 1975-1978 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 340)
      - Weisser, Gerhard, 1979-1982 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 341)
      - * Weissman, Fred S.
        See Selfhelp of Emigres from Central Europe, Inc.
      - Wheeler, Robert F., 1975-1977 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 342)
      - * White, Ernest
        See Weiss, Ernst
      - * White, Jeannette
        See Weiss, Jeannette.
      - Winkler, Ernst, 1946-1983 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 343)
        Winkler, Karin.
      - Wittenberg, Isca Salzberger, 1973-1983 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 344)
      - Witzsch, Günter, 1973-1976 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 345)
      - Witzsch, Günter, 1977-1983 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 346)
      - Wolf, Elisabeth, 1953-1966 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 347)
      - Wolf, Elisabeth, 1967-1980 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 348)
      - Wolins, Martin, 1954-1983 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 349)
      - Wülker, Gabriele, 1954-1980 (Box 14 (2.2.1-Professional correspondence (selection based ), Folder 350)
    - Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, including some with former students), 1933-1984; 2.2.2; 1043 folders containing approx. 6835 items of correspondence
      Most of the folders contain only several items each, however, all deal with various aspects of Walter Friedländer's professional activities in the social work and social welfare fields.
      - Abbott, Kenneth, 1968-1979 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 1)
      - Abendroth, Wolfgang, 1974 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 2)
      - Abraham, Edith, 1948 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 3)
      - Abramowicz, A. (Al Schifrin, Sascha Schwarz), 1937 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 4)
      - Abramson, Dr, 1933 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 5)
      - Achinger, Hans, 1958-1976 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 6)
      - Adler, Jenny, 1949 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 7)
      - Adler, Frau Dr. K., 1933 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 8)
      - Adler, Michael, 1980 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 9)
      - Akura, Patrick, 1980 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 10)
      - Alber, Jens, 1977-1978 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 11)
      - Albrecht, Günter, 1974-1980 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 12)
      - Albrecht, Stan L., 1983 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 13)
      - Alexander, Chauncey, 1969-1982 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 14)
      - Alexander, Hilde, 1950 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 15)
      - Alexander, Mildred, 1973-1979 (Box 15 (2.2.2-Professional correspondence (lesser amounts, ), Folder 16)